Passing messages over topics between publishers and subscribers is
パブリッシャーとサブスクライバー間でトピックに関するメッセージを渡すことは
useful but it's not a one size fits all communications solution.
便利ですが万人向けの通信ソリューションではありません
There are times when a request response pattern is useful.
要求応答パターンの方が向いている場合があります
For these types of interactions,
こうしたタイプの相互作用に対して
ROS provides what are called services.
ROS はサービスと呼ばれるものを提供します
Like topics, services allow the passing of messages between nodes.
サービスはトピックのように ノード間のメッセージ通信を可能にします
However, unlike topics, a service is not a bus
サービスがトピックと違うのは これがバスではなく
and there are no publishers or subscribers associated with them.
関連したパブリッシャーもサブスクライバーもないことです
Instead, nodes interacting via services do so on
サービス経由で相互作用するノードは 1 対 1 をベースに
a one to one basis using a request and response messages.
要求メッセージと応答メッセージを使用し これを実行します
Let's take a look at how a service might be used in the example we've been developing.
今まで開発してきたこの例で サービスがどのように使用されるかを見てみましょう
Let's say that the behavior executor node wants to capture an image from the camera.
Behavior Executor (動作実行者) ノードがカメラからの画像をキャプチャするとします
We could just have it subscribe to the camera images topic.
画像は camera_images (カメラ画像) トピックにサブスクライブするだけです
It would then receive a new image each time the camera node publishes one.
ここでは camera ノードから画像が発行されると 毎回新しい画像を受信します
However, this might be undesirable if
しかしながら Executor ノードでもっと間隔を空けて
the executor only wants to capture an image every once in a while.
画像をキャプチャするには この状況は望ましくありません
Instead of subscribing to the camera images topic here,
camera_images トピックにサブスクライブするのではなく
we'll define a new service for the camera node.
新しいサービスをこの camera ノードに定義します
Let's call it capture image.
これを capture_image (キャプチャ画像) としましょう
The request message definition might be a custom message type
要求メッセージの定義は exposure time (露光時間) というカスタムメッセージタイプになり
called exposure time and the response might just be an image message.
応答はシンプルに image (画像) メッセージになります
By issuing a service call to the capture image service,
capture_image サービスにサービス呼び出しを発行すると
the behavior executor node or any other node for that matter,
Behavior Executor ノードやその他の関係するノードは camera ノードに対して
is able to request the camera should capture an image with a given exposure time setting.
指定された露光時間設定で画像をキャプチャするよう要求できます
The camera node will then respond to the request
camera ノードは 結果の画像を含むメッセージを送信することで
by sending a message containing the resulting image.
要求に応答します